Pallavi Aggarwal

 P New York, US
 J (201)-918-7448
 ■ pa.pallaviagg@gmail.com

https://linkedin.com/in/pallavi-aggarwal https://github.com/pallavi16 https://www.pallaviaggarwal.com

SUMMARY

Aspiring Technical Product Manager with 5 years of experience in developing web applications and hardware products. Expertise in Javascript (React/Angular), and SQL. In-depth knowledge of Agile methodologies and Experience with Full Product Management Lifecycles. AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, Certified Scrum Product Owner (CSPO) by ScrumAlliance.org and Certified Technical Product Manager by PMHQ.

SKILLS

Product Management: Roadmap Planning, KPIs, Excellent Written and Verbal Communication, Leadership Technical Skills: JavaScript (React/Angular), SQL, REST APIs, Node.js, Cloud Technologies (AWS/GCP)

Tools: JIRA, Figma, Google Analytics, Power BI, Git, Miro, Visual Studio

Project Management: Agile Methodologies, Scrum

EXPERIENCE

Cofounder, KRPS Technologies Pvt. Ltd, New Delhi, India

July 2019 - June 2023

- Hardware Tech Startup to build cutting-edge sensor-based (touchless) tech products.
- Juggled between multiple tasks varying from research and development, creating Product Roadmaps to testing, architect Product Design
- Managed team workflows, ensuring alignment with organizational goals and feature-build priorities.
- Extensive research to build IoT devices, AI/ML technologies (Training Machine Learning Models)
- Solve Complex Business and Hardware Problems With Technology

Technical Product Manager, Allied Technologies, Tennessee, US (Remote)

June 2022 - Sept 2022

- Improved the software development team's delivery rate by 30 percent by introducing Atlassian's product suite, specifically JIRA and Confluence, to the product team.
- Introduced the scrum framework to the organization, and trained 3 engineers on agile best practices
- Managed the entire product development lifecycle(SDLC) for multiple clients and conducted extensive A/B testing and cross-device testing.
- Used AWS S3 to host websites
- Undertook Product Scrum Master responsibilities to translate over 150 user stories into a clear, detailed Product Requirement Document (PRD) for the software development team.

Frontend Engineer, Huntsman Cancer Institute, Utah, US

Jan 2018 - May 2019

- Redesigned the internal web application 'Research Admin' in use by 100+ employees, resulting in 20+ new, improved features, reduced load time by 15percent.
- Utilized Angular2 to develop components for the backend team, Spring MVC to consume the REST APIs, JavaScript, CSS3 to display the data in the front-end.
- Improved user interaction by migrating the existing codebase from Angular JS to Angular 2.
- Collaborated with the back-end team, management team to assess improved performance through user testing.
- Participating in daily scrum meetings, sprint planning, unit testing and bug fixes.

Junior Frontend Engineer, music.iLuv, California, US

Aug 2017 - Dec 2017

- Assisted a team of developers in front-end design of a demo application 'music.iLuv'.
- Understood the software development lifecycle and was involved in requirement gathering, analysis, design, and testing.

EDUCATION

MS in Computer Engineering, University of Utah, US

Aug 2015 – Jul 2017

Advanced Computer Networks, Artificial Intelligence, Database Systems, Operating Systems

BTech in Electronics Engineering, GGSIPU, New Delhi, India

Aug 2011 - Jun 2015

Integrated Circuits, Digital Electronics, Network Communication, Object Oriented Programming